Preliminary Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Ed George Papers, 1960s-1990s and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Ed George papers 1960s-1990s and undated
J. Walter Thompson Company
14.2 linear feet Extent: 1250 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00703
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, some of the materials in this collection are not immediately accessible, because they require further processing before use.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Ed George Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2001, with a subsequent gift in 2009.
Biographical Note
The J. Walter Thompson Company was founded in New York, N.Y., in 1864, and is one of the world's largest advertising agencies.
Collection Overview
Ed George was a longtime executive for JWT, serving in a number of offices. The collection contains an assortment of items reflecting his creative career, comprising primarily finished advertisements for a variety of clients, in formats including videotapes of commercials, filmstrips, reel-to-reel audio tapes, and print advertisements. Also includes ad mockups; package designs; original art; billboard sheets; and other advertising memorabilia. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Accession (2009-0102) (4.0 lin. ft.; 500 items; dated 1960s-1990s) includes George's sketches, mockups, and drafts for print, billboard, and television commercial advertisements created for JWT, FC&B, and Playboy. Also includes original art and comics for Car and Driver magazine.
Subject Headings
George, Ed; J. Walter Thompson Company; Advertising -- History; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Executives; Advertising agencies -- Employees; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising, Outdoor -- Posters; Commercial art; Billboards; Billboards -- Design and construction; Billboards -- United States; Packaging; Audiotapes; Videocassettes; Phonograph records; Filmstrips; Memorabilia; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2002-0196
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Videotapes of TV commercials, 1981-1985 (Box 1)
      (Includes commercials for Blue Cross, Ford, Hawaii Express, and Kawasaki.)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Videotapes of TV commercials, 1981-1982 and undated (Box 2)
      (Includes commercials for Kawasaki, Oscar Mayer, Monroe, Pepsi, and 7-Up.)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Videotapes of TV commercials, 1982-1983 and undated (Box 3)
      (Includes commercials for Form and Function, 7-Up historical ads, Hawaii Express, and Kawasaki.)
    - Film Strip, 35mm, Seven-Up, undated (Box 3)
    - Filmstrips, 16mm, undated (Box 3)
      (Includes commercials for Bankamericard, Hamm's Beer, Kawasaki, Ken-L-Ration, Mazda, Murine, Oscar Mayer, Sclitz Beer, Seven-Up, Simonize Wax, Sterling Beer, and Volvo.)
    - Reel-to-reel audio tape, Burger King, undated (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Filmstrips, 16mm, undated (Box 4)
      (Includes commercials for Film Fair, Kawasaki, and Seven-Up.)
    - Reel-to-Reel audio tapes, undated (Box 4)
      (Includes radio spots for Alligator, FAygo Soft Drinks, Kawasaki, Oscar Mayer, Pepsi, and 7-Up.)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Filmstrips, 16mm, undated (Box 5)
      (Includes commercials for Bank Americard, Hamm's Beer, Kawasaki Truck, Ken-L-Ration Burger, Monroe, Murine, Oscar Mayer, Sclitz Beer, and 7-Up.)
    - Photographic Slides, Eaton Truck Parts, undated (Box 5)
    - Reel-to-Reel audio tapes, n.d (Box 5)
      (Includes radio spots for Burger King, Hammond Aquarius, and Sterling Beer.)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Memorabilia, misc. (Box 6)
      (Includes JWT commemorative materials, and various client memorabilia and promotional toys.)
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - Small Advertising Prints, ca. 1980s (Box 7)
      (Includes prints from Burger King, Champion, ford, Hawaii Espress, JWT logos, Kawasaki, and Payless Drug Stores.)
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated (Box 8)
      (Includes ads for All Sports News, Booth Newspapers, Champion Sparkplugs, and Eaton Truck Parts.)
  - Contents of Box 9: (Box 9)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated (Box 9)
      (Includes ads for Ford and Hamm's Beer.)
  - Contents of Box 10: (Box 10)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated (Box 10)
      (Includes ads for Harley Davidson, Kawasaki, Oscar Mayer, 7-Up, and Sterling Beer.)
  - Contents of Box 11: (Box 11)
    - Sketches and Packaging Designs for Various Cigarette Brands, undated (Box 11)
  - Contents of Box 12: (Box 12)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated, Oversize Materials (Box 12)
      (Includes ads for All Sports News, Detroit Grand Prix, and Ford Dealer Association.)
  - Contents of Box 13: (Box 13)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated, Oversize Materials (Box 13)
      (Includes ads for Ford Festiva.)
  - Contents of Box 14: (Box 14)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated, Oversize Materials (Box 14)
      (Includes ads for Ford.)
  - Contents of Box 15: (Box 15)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated, Oversize Materials (Box 15)
  - Contents of Box 16: (Box 16)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated, Oversize Materials (Box 16)
      (Includes ads for Ford Taurus, Hammond Organ, Hawaii Express, and J. Walter Thompson.)
  - Contents of Box 17: (Box 17)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated, Oversize Materials (Box 17)
      (Includes ads for Kawasaki, Ken-L-Ration, Marine Corps Recruiting, and 7-Up.)
  - Contents of Box 18: (Box 18)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated, Large Oversize Materials (Box 18)
      (Includes ads for Chicago Herald Tribune, Claussen, and Ford.)
  - Contents of Box 19: (Box 19)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated, Large Oversize Materials (Box 19)
      (Includes ads for Ford Dealer Association.)
  - Contents of Box 20: (Box 20)
    - Print Ads and Mockups, undated, Large Oversize Materials (Box 20)
      (Includes ads for Ford Dealer Association and 7-Up.)
  - Contents of Oversize tubes 1-2: (Tube 1-2)
    - Billboard sheets: Rainlap 30-ish "Un-Un and Away" Zeppelin design 70-8 (Tube 1-2)
- Accession (2009-0102), 1960s-1995, (4 boxes)
  Accession (2009-0102) (4.0 lin. ft.; 500 items; dated 1960s-1990s) includes George's sketches, mockups, and drafts for print, billboard, and television commercial advertisements created for JWT, FC&B, and Playboy. Also includes original art and comics for Car and Driver magazine.
  - JWT Chicago (Box 21)
    - 7-Up outdoor, 1960s (Box 21)
    - Businessmen drawings, 1960s-1970s (Box 21)
  - FC&B Los Angeles
    - Smokey the Bear (Box 21)
    - United California Bank (Box 21)
    - Taco Bell (Box 21)
    - Film House (Box 21)
  - JWT Detroit
    - The Fall Soldiers, late 1970s (Box 21)
    - Kawasaki, late 1970s (Box 21)
    - State of Michigan, late 1970s (Box 21)
    - Hawaii Express logo designs (Box 21)
    - Rampage Racing logo designs (Box 21)
    - Ford vehicle proposals, 1980s (Box 21)
    - Ford technology newspaper advertisements, 1980s (Box 21)
    - Jaguar, late 1980s (Box 21)
    - Chatham supermarkets, late 1970s (Box 21)
  - JWT New York
    - Burger King, late 1970s (Box 21)
    - Kodak color, late 1970s (Box 21)
  - JWT Los Angeles
    - Kawasaki television boards, early 1980s (Box 21)
  - Playboy
    - Art Institute of Chicago (Box 21)
    - Hollywood Bowl, 1980 (Box 21)
    - The Balloon Lady Red Balloon advertisement (Box 21)
    - A Whale for the Killing (Box 21)
  - Color drawings
    - Professor Mazda's Amazing Rotary Engine Flying Machine (Box 21)
    - Assorted illustrations (Box 21)
  - Panoz Motorsports letterhead and logos (Box 21)
  - Mazda newspaper, outdoor, and television boards (Box 22)
  - Frozen french fries (Box 22)
  - (Box 22)
  - Comics and sketches about cars and driving, including some drafts for Car and Driver magazine (5 folders) (Box 23)
  - Car and Driver magazines, 1988-1990 (Box 23)
  - Ford cars book mockups and proofs, 1980s-1990s (3 folders) (Box 23)
  - Ford cars personal portfolio, 1995 (Box 23)
  - Ford Windstar book mockups, 1995 (Box 23)
  - Kawasaki (Box 23)
  - Ford vehicle oversize booklets and pamphlet proofs and mockups, 1980s-1990s (Box 24)